Guide to the Neighbors Thanking Neighbors Fire Fund records 2000
Montana Historical Society
Neighbors Thanking Neighbors Fire Fund records
2000
Montana Historical Society Archives
MC 302
Neighbors Thanking Neighbors Fire Fund (Helena, Mont.)
0.2 linear feet
This collection consists of materials pertaining to the fund raising events sponsored by the Neighbors Thanking Neighbors Fire Fund. Records include correspondence from state officials supporting the events; emails (hard copies) from Montanans expressing gratitude to fire fighters; art work by children expressing gratitude for assistance given to their families; receipts and donor lists; publicity materials that announced fundraiser events, etc.
Historical Note:
The Neighbors Thanking Neighbors Fire Fund was established during the 2000 forest fire season in Helena, Montana. Four large fires burned in the Helena region that year, causing numerous evacuations and several home losses. The Fire Fund organization was established to assist families affected by the fires and to thank the fire fighters and volunteers.
This collection consists of materials relating to fund raising events sponsored by the Neighbors Thanking Neighbors Fire Fund to assist Helena area residents affected by the summer of 2000 fire season, and show community support for those who fought the fires-professionals and volunteers alike. Records include correspondence from state officials supporting the events; Hard copies of emails from Montanans expressing gratitude to fire fighters; art work by children expressing gratitude for assistance given to their families; receipts and donor lists; event sign-in sheets; and publicity materials that announced fundraiser events.
Arranged into three series: 1) Incoming Correspondence, 2) Financial Records, and 3) Miscellany. Some material housed in Archives Map Case. See inventory below for more information.
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Neighbors Thanking Neighbors Fire Fund (Helena, Mont.)
Helena (Mont.)--Social life and customs
Fire fighters--Montana; Forest fires--Montana--Jefferson County; Forest fires--Montana--Lewis and Clark County; Fund raising--Montana--Helena
Montana
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Incoming Correspondence
  - Letters of support from state and national officials,(including Judy Martz, Rick Hill, Max Baucus, and Pat Haffey), 2000 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
  - E-mails of support from citizens (includes expressions of support, personal observations, poetry, etc.), 2000 (Box-folder 1 / 2-3)
- Financial Records
  - Donation letters, fundraiser information, etc., 2000 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
- Miscellany
  - Children's artwork (portion of an exhibit), 2000 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - Events sign-in sheets, 2000 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - Publicity materials, 2000 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
  - Publicity materials [Oversize: Archives Map Case], 2000 (Oversize-folder 1)